I'm not trying to sell you this book.
I don't even care if you read it.
There will be no link in the description
where I make 30 or 40p per
person that buys it. But this book,
I actually need to thank a huge amount for
helping me work online, travel the world,
and I probably never gave it enough
credit for how it's truly helped me.
Now, for a lot of you watching this,
you have no idea who I am.
You might have seen this book in an
airport and gone, "Oh,
that looks stupid." Who
only works four hours a week?
Then you've seen this video,
and there's some twat
in a vest sat here talking about it.
But if you give me a few minutes,
I'm going to explain the same lessons you
can get
from this. Nowadays,
every single person wants to be an online
coach, but I was
doing this in 2017. My first objection,
saying to people, I go, "How can you
personal train someone online?" It
was like saying to someone,
you're an online
plumber.
But it was definitely what I learned in
this book that permitted me to be
one of the first to ever do it.
Quick story. I was in Croatia.
I went to Ultra Music Festival in Croatia,
which is a fantastic
music festival for any of you considering
going to one.
I know you've got so many options around
the world.
You just get a good crowd of people in
Croatia.
But anyway, I did one too many pingers,
and you know where it's not just a come
down, you've got the zaps,
where every time you're falling asleep,
you get a little
zap. So I decided that me
and my friends should go to
that waterfall in Croatia.
And we go there,
and we get a little minivan on the way
there, and there's a guy
next to me in the back. He was American,
I think he was from Miami, and he had his
laptop out. I was like, "Mate,
you're in Croatia.
What are you doing with your laptop?" He
says, "I'm working." I said, "How can you
be working? We're in Croatia." He goes,
"Oh, I've got an accountancy business.
I work online." I was like,
"What?" I said,
"How can you work online if your
business is in Miami?" He says to me,
"James," he didn't know my name.
He said, "Mate." Didn't say mate,
he's American.
He said,
"You should read 'The 4-Hour Workweek.'"
So I made a note of it on my
phone. When I got home, went onto Amazon,
bought it, and I did what every single
person does.
This just kind of sits on your windowsill.
And I remember thinking, I
was just about to start reading it.
In the UK,
we only get about two weeks of summer a
year.
I said, "When it's next sunny
and I've got a gap between clients,
I'm going to go
home, sit in my parents' garden
and read it." But I'll never forget,
one of my best
mates at the time, he saw the book
and he goes, "Ah, it's a
good concept,
but it would never work in the real life."
So I reckon I put off
reading it for about another month,
and I went out in the garden.
I started reading the first three, four,
five pages, and it became apparent to me
that my mate hadn't read it.
So I said to him,
"Why did you tell me that?" All he
did was read the bit on the back.
But anyway,
the main concept of this book is
defining something
which I haven't actually mentioned in
years, which Tim Ferriss
calls the new rich.
We've got people out there that are rich,
rich, they've got
loads of money.
But the new rich isn't about having a
million dollars in the bank.
It's about having freedom,
it's about being able to travel.
It's about managing your own diary.
It's about being in charge of your own
business, which for the majority of time,
not many people have had the opportunity
of doing.
Rewind to a magic mushroom trip I did a
few years ago in Sydney.
I was sat on a beach called Milk Beach,
and I remember looking over into the city
where you've got all the big corporate
buildings, and there's loads of yachts
between us. And I remember thinking, "Hmm,
I bet all of those yachts are owned by
super wealthy people,
but I wonder how many of those wealthy
people are trapped
inside those skyscraper buildings in the
city." I was like, "They might have
100 times more money than me
and a boat that I don't have,
but I'm the one sat on a
beach at 3:00 PM on a Tuesday,
and they're the person wearing a shirt
and tie in
an office that they can't leave until
5:30." So I was kind of thinking to
myself,
"You might be richer,
but I could be wealthier." And that
was kind of the concept
of the new rich. And if I
was to say to you as someone,
do you want to have
objectively the most money in your bank
account, or would you rather have the
autonomy to travel whenever you want,
turn every single holiday into a business
class trip, which is what the new rich do.
Oh, you're going to LA for Coachella,
James?
Hmm,
sounds to me like you're going there for a
business meeting coincidentally on
the same weekend. That
is not tax evasion advice.
And another thing
that I never really thought about until
reading this book is I
never really got excited about the concept
of retirement.
Hey,
you're going to work really hard at
school, stay out of trouble.
You're going to go to university,
get in loads of debt.
You're going to get a 9:00 to 5:00.
You're going to work really hard.
You're going to pay off all your debt.
And then just when you pay off that debt,
you're going to get another debt, and
that debt is going to be massive,
and it's going to be for a house.
And you're going to pay it off for 30
years.
So if you buy a house at 25,
which no one is, most of them
are buying them at what?
30 to 35. 30 years, that takes you to 65.
So then you're just paying off debt, debt,
debt, debt, debt.
And then at 65, you paid off that debt,
and now you can stop
working. And then you get your pension,
which is a lot less of the money that you
used to earn,
but now you haven't got debt,
and you might own your house, or you
might not. And then you're 65 now.
You can travel the
world and do all of those things
that you couldn't do because you only had
two
weeks of annual leave a year for the last
60 years. That never excited me.
I was like, "Hmm, between 25 and 35,
I have less than half the energy
that I had at
25. So at 45, if that halves again,
trust me, by the time I reach 65,
I'm just going to want to sit at home on a
rocking chair being left alone." The
idea of having to wait decades to be able
to enjoy yourself never
resonated with me. So
when I read this book and I was like,
"Wow, retirement is
actually a worst-case scenario."
If you never make anything of your
life and your businesses never do
that well,
then maybe you give up at 65 and
retire. But for some reason,
we're kind of brainwashed into thinking
that's the
best outcome. Now, hypocritically,
my dad retired. He loves it.
Absolutely loves it.
Does nothing with his days.
He's feeding ducks with a bit of bread in
the garden.
He even somehow realized there
were Egyptian geese at the top of a tree.
He can barely use WhatsApp,
so I don't know how he figured that out.
But for me, I'm not saying for everyone,
but for me, I couldn't imagine
anything worse than retiring.
Today's Christmas Eve.
The thought of having today off makes me
slightly depressed.
What,
I'm just going to have a day off because a
fictional character that comes
down a chimney gives kids presents.
He's coming tomorrow or tonight.
If there was someone
that came from another country to give
your kid a gift So it
behaves. It's just got pedo vibes.
Now, it wasn't just this book
that pushed me over the edge to working
online, but it got me started.
It got me realizing
that the digital world that we
live in is very different to the world
that came before.
We can bypass that system of having to
work for decades to then stop working.
And there was actually a guy in Dubai who
messaged me when I was personal training
in Bracknell. His name was Cliff. He said,
"Hi, James.
I want to do personal training with you."
I go, "Cool.
Come in for a consult." He goes, "I can't.
I live in Dubai." I was like, "Hmm,
kind of a long way to come in for a
consult,
mate." He goes,
"You'll just train me online." I was like,
"How am I going to do
that?" He goes, "I don't know.
You'll figure it out." He had followed me
online,
and he said that all the PTs around him in
Dubai were kind of bellends, and he
didn't care that I didn't know what I
was doing.
He would rather have me train him online,
and that's how it began.
Started training Cliff,
and then before you know it, I
was training Pippa, then
before you know it, I
was training a few other people.
That, combined with this book, meant
that within a few months, I left England,
I left all my clients,
and I started training people online from
Australia.
I was backpacking down the East Coast.
I was charging 55 pounds a week.
And again,
this isn't a video about pricing,
but I just said I'm going to charge my
hourly rate for a week.
And the reason being is, for them, it
meant they didn't just stand with me for
an hour.
They could get three or four workouts
and daily points of contact with me.
And for me, it meant
that I could service
that person in less than an hour.
Because when you sell an hour of your time
for just a bit of money, no matter if
you're super productive in that session
or not, you get paid the same.
Whereas now,
I was rewarded for the more efficient I
was, the more caffeine I had,
the quicker I could service a client,
the more money I was earning per hour.
For the first time,
I could move away from having to earn a
fixed amount in eight
hours to being able to earn considerably
more as long as I was productive.
One of the golden rules in this book
is about delegation.
Now,
I disagree with a lot of the concepts in
here about delegation.
It kind of makes it feel like everything
should be delegated.
But Tim Ferriss does have a very good
point where he asks a question.
If something needs to be done,
do you need to do it?
And if the answer is yes,
then you should do it.
But if you don't,
you should consider delegating it.
Even editing this video,
I would love to edit this video,
but considering Declan
can do it,
and he can actually do it better than me,
I should give it to him so I
can go away and do other things that
are more productive to the business.
I also start doing
that in 2017 with personal training.
Although I was the personal training
brand, the fact that I could hire another
coach to do that for me meant
that I could spend my time working on the
element of
the business that would actually be more
profitable, which would be making content.
It was only breaking free of this belief
that the business that I had had to
exist within the four walls
that I worked within, that I
was able to build several
empires that take over the world.
And the reason I'm telling you this
is that it's
really important for you guys to
appreciate that there
is a world outside there,
you might not have figured it out yet,
of business that doesn't involve you
getting
paid a certain amount per hour, and
that doesn't involve you having to be in a
fixed location forever.
The biggest problem I see
that I definitely had
in corporate world,
which I worked in for years before
operating my own business,
was they have the 9:00 till 5:00,
or actually it was probably 8:30 till
5:30.
And again,
you get punished with traffic because you
have to always get to the
office a little bit earlier to avoid
traffic,
but you still have to leave at the
same time.
If you get in 10 minutes earlier,
you don't get to leave 10 minutes
earlier.
But whatever work you had for the day,
you become very accustomed to
stretching it across the day.
It's called Parkinson's law.
The amount of time you give to a task,
it will take that long to complete.
No matter what it is that you're doing,
you are not rewarded for getting things
done faster in an office. If anything,
you're now just left there with two hours
at
the end of the day. You sit there going,
"It's 3:30.
I've got nothing left to do." You have to
look busy for two hours, which is
actually probably more difficult than the
work that you're doing. I know.
I did it for years.
And you develop so many bad habits from
that.
Whereas when you're running your own
business and operating your own books and
doing everything yourself,
you can determine how hard you want to
work at different
parts of the day.
I also have insanely bad ADHD,
and I just do
not know when I'm going to be productive
in a day and when I'm not.
Some days, 7:00 a.m.,
I'm firing on all cylinders.
Other days at 7:00 a.m.,
I'm doom scrolling on Instagram.
Some nights at 7:00 p.m.,
I'm exhausted watching TV.
Other nights, I'm getting ideas
and I'm scripting videos for the next day.
For so many of us from a personality
standpoint, if you're someone
that just loves
going in,
having the office 9:00 till 5:00,
sitting there and doing your thing,
this video is not for you.
But some of you probably feel like you're
a square being
put in a triangle hole.
And although some of the delegation stuff
in this is just a
bit wishy-washy,
the thing about getting an EA online
or someone
online to do stuff for cheaper than it
would cost you in real life, I have
used. When I had my podcast cranking,
I actually hired a lady called
Mary from the Philippines, and she got,
I think, 10 US dollars an hour.
And I gave her the Instagram logins to my
Instagram, and I gave her the simple
task of, one,
identifying conversations
that could be important, and two,
saying thank you to people
that had shared my podcast.
Now,
it can seem like a relatively
insignificant thing, but for me, for 10 US
dollars an hour,
to pay her 50 bucks a day,
I could then make sure that every
single person that
was kind enough to share my podcast got a
little message going,
"Thank you. Appreciate it."
That could just spur them on to carry on
sharing it
every time they listen to it,
which could have a profound impact on the
growth of
the podcast,
which would then have a profound impact on
the growth of the brand,
book sales or whatever it is.
So sometimes if there's any of
that manual labor that you can offset,
this book
definitely opened up my eyes to that.
Not every industry can be pushed online,
but a lot of them can, whether it's an
editor, whether you are a consultant.
Even as a personal trainer, for years,
everyone thought that has to be done in
person.
But if you can get people to start using
your services online, you can
actually start to deliver a better
product.
One of the premises of this book is
that say you are employed in a corporate
9:00
till 5:00 job,
that you start taking time away from work
to work
remotely, but then you work better remote,
and you create a case that you
can go to your employer and say, "Hey,
on the days that I don't come to the
office,
I seem to perform better. Therefore,
if you want me to perform my best,
you should
let me work from home more."
And you can actually do the exact same
thing as an
online coach.
One thing I never realized
that my online clients were going to get
better results than my in-person clients,
just the matter of fact that I would
spend more frequent times checking in with
them on a daily basis,
and that I'd be setting them more workouts
that they had to do themselves.
So many clients that you have in person
kind of just lean on you to be the
deliverer of the session,
and they probably don't come in any time
that you're not
with them. We've all had the clients
that have come in and you go, "Oh, did you
come in at all?" "I
was really busy last week." Whereas
if they're online, they
have to do it themselves.
And something as simple as a strategy of
saying to a
client, "Hey,
every evening before you go to bed,
send me a screenshot of your
MyFitnessPal." For you,
that takes 10 seconds to go, "Oh, cool.
Dave hit his calories. Well done."
But for them, that means
that they're accruing
days on days on days on days of actually
hitting the goals that you set them.
Then another thing from this
that I think was massive was the fact
that you can
automate so much of the sales process.
Which as a PT on the gym floor,
I had to manually go out there, prospect,
talk to
people, book them in for the consult,
turn up to the consult, talk them,
take them
through a little session,
then at the session, try and close them.
Whereas actually now the majority of all
my sales online are done overnight with
automations. For instance,
there's a link that I put in almost every
single YouTube
video that says,
"If you want 30 ways in 30 days to improve
your business." And
when people sign up to that
Which you can do.
You can literally sign up to steal it
if you want.
Every day they get an email that's sent,
and it's already been pre-written.
And by the end of that automation,
they're either converted to join the
course or
they're not. But either way,
my sole job then is to get people to join
the
automation.
So if you think about this video,
goes on YouTube, whether it gets
5,000 views, 10,000 views, whatever,
suddenly a certain percentage of those
people
are going to listen to this verbal cue to
click that link in the description, then
they're going to sign up. From there,
the majority of them are probably going to
think that they're too impenetrable.
They go, "James, do you know what?
I'm going to read your emails over 30
days, and there's no way
that you're going to
convince me that your program's good
enough." Yet 17% of people
that read them sign up. So
that automation is there in place
tomorrow, the next
day, the next day. Then
when people become clients, there
is an onboarding
process,
and then I will talk to them inside the
mentorship.
So everything is automated.
From this video to our first point of
contact, I have created systems in place,
so I don't need to be there.
So if someone comes up to me and goes,
"Oh, James,
I'm interested in your course,"
I say, "Look, go watch a YouTube video.
If you like it,
click on the link in the description,"
and the whole sales process
is taken care of. Another thing
that this book definitely helped me with
was
appreciating how valuable my time is.
Now,
if I did not have a partner right now,
and I was single, I would probably
consider hiring a cook or a chef.
Chefs aren't actually that
expensive,
but you could hire one to come around
and do six hours of cooking on
a Sunday afternoon. You could say to them,
"Hey, mate, I'll pay you extra if you
go do the shopping for me.
I want to have 200 grams of protein a day,
roughly
2,500 calories.
Can you make it happen?" The chef could
then go away, get a massive
shopping list and order.
Then I could pay them for five,
six hours where they cook
it up, put it in Tupperware,
put it in my fridge.
Let's say that was to cost me hundreds of
dollars per week.
If that means I don't have to go to the
supermarket every day,
that I don't have to
go out during my lunch break,
that I don't have to cook and clean
and wash my pans
and everything else,
I could be saving myself hours throughout
the week, and I just
need to ask myself, "How valuable
are my hours?" When I lived in London,
I would
skateboard everywhere I could,
but sometimes it would be more
profitable for me to get an expensive Uber
somewhere.
So let's say me skateboarding to the tube
station, change on the tube a couple of
times, get off,
skateboard to the other place
was 45 minutes.
If I was to go in an expensive Uber
and it was an hour,
sometimes I would take the
Uber because even if it
was to cost me 80 or 90 pounds, I get to
sit in the Uber and work. And
that work might look pretty fucked up
compared to
what other people consider work.
But I would say to myself,
if I sit in the Uber
and answer story questions,
which can seem like fucking around, I'm
actually curating content
that I get to determine and decide
which questions I
ask in front of tens of thousands of
people.
And then I could put a call to action
within those story questions somewhere,
which
could then compel maybe a few thousand
people to go into an automation where they
can get a sale.
One of my old business mentors had a
Ferrari.
Don't really like Ferraris myself.
But he used to get the bus to work because
he could work on the bus.
If he drives his Ferrari, sweet,
it's nice Ferrari, sit in London traffic.
But if he gets the bus from outside his
house to the gym that he used to work at,
he gets to do emails,
he gets to respond to people,
he gets to book people in for
calls. He gets to do all of that.
So sometimes you do need to consider where
you
can save time in your life for it to be
more profitable.
Same reason getting a cleaner.
Paying someone to do the things so you can
work
more only benefits the net equation.
Even Declan here.
You cost twice as much as my Porsche does
a week.
But he gets me time back
that I can then spend either working
or being with my family. And that,
at the end of the day,
is a thought of the new
rich. The old rich would go,
"I'll do everything myself so I can have
the most
money in the bank account." The new rich
go, "Have half of my money.
Give me the freedom. Give me the time.
Give me the fact
that I can go traveling and know
that things are going to get
done." And better yet,
Declan can go traveling,
and he can work while he's away
because he's one of the new rich now.
Where are you going over Christmas?
Queensland. Guy is going out of state,
but he'll have an SD card on him, and just
having one of these on him means he can
earn cash whilst he's traveling.
He's not tied down. Your family
are going to go, "What are you doing,
Declan?
It's Christmas." You go,
"I'm working." "How can you be working
from Queensland?
I thought your employer
was in New South Wales." You go,
"I'm part of the new rich.
Shut your mouth." You go, "Here's $100.
Shut up." Don't know
if that's how you talk to your family.
That's how I talk to mine. Now,
one of the craziest things
is I've reread this book
over the last few days, and it
is nowhere near as impressive as I
remember
it. In my mind, I was like, "This
is a Bible.
If you read this,
you'll become a millionaire."
But it's not.
It's actually, sorry, Tim Ferriss,
a relatively average
book.
But I've come to realize now it wasn't the
book that really changed
everything. It was the book
that just changed my beliefs of what
normal was like. Because we
are all brainwashed and gaslit into having
this similar kind of structure as to how
work looks. But we get to define it.
We get to determine whether it's online,
whether it's in person.
And so many of you right now will be like,
"Oh, but in my
profession, we can't do that.
I'm a barber, and I can't cut
someone's hair from online." Patrick's
brand that's in
Selfridges.
Went surfing with the guy the other day.
Harrods.
Opened a barber shop,
saw an opportunity for a hair product
that he thought
would potentially be better than all the
others.
Barbers then make incredible hair product.
You could be a lawyer
and you're there getting $800 an hour as a
lawyer.
"I can't be a lawyer online." Well,
you could do consultancy, or you could
be someone that gives out free assets so
that people understand the
legislative procedure of a divorce.
And you could be the divorce guy,
and then you can make content on YouTube
about
divorce. And then you could be like, "Hey,
guys, if you want to know where your
legal ramifications
are surrounding a divorce,
pop your email address in.
Over the next two months,
I'm going to bring you up to speed on
2025's
legal situation for divorce." Then you
could have a team of
killer divorce lawyers who go in there
and make sure that she doesn't take you
to the cleaners, bro. It's not
that your profession can't do it.
You just might have the vision
that I had for years, looking down
and pigeonholing
and going, "Oh,
I help people count their reps,
and that's all I can do." Here are
the key things that I implemented from the
book that I think you should do with
your life.
Don't wait till you're 65 to enjoy
yourself.
Create a business and a system
and something that means right now
that you can
have mini retirements. In 2018, I
was going out with an Australian girl.
I was on her visa, and
that relationship imploded.
I became depressed.
I also went through a legal situation,
which wasn't great, but Due to the
nature of building an online business,
I went to Bali, and I tell you what,
crying
on a moped in Bali
is better than crying in your bed at home.
Lived in Bali for three months,
went to the Middle East,
ended up in the UK for six
months,
went to Coachella with some strangers from
the internet. Why?
Because I was working online.
When I look back now, and like I say,
I'm only
35,
I could retire from having fun right now
because I'm tired. I'm exhausted.
But I look back at all these little mini
periods of my life where I never stopped
working,
but I definitely dialed it back to enjoy
myself.
I'm so grateful I didn't wait another 30
years to start having fun.
You can go to so many parts of the world
that are just significantly cheaper than
where you are now. Relative income
is something that's really important.
So there's no point earning--
People in London do this.
They earn good money.
They earn £100,000 a year.
You can barely get by with that in London.
But if you were to go live in Argentina
or Bali or Thailand, you'd
be so wealthy there because your income
relative to what you spend would be
massive.
You can also do this without geographical
restrictions.
For so many of you, take this advice
if you want or don't,
I moved back in with my
parents when I was 25, maybe even 26. Why?
So I could flip the relative income
spectrum.
Move back in with my parents,
save £1,000 a month, spend it on travel.
Sevens, I was playing. Norway, Sweden,
Denmark,
Dubai. Where was it? Didn't matter.
For so many of you,
if moving back in with your parents at
stage in your life when
you're single frees up some income so you
can travel a bit more, that's a good
deal. Just say, "Look, Mum, Dad,
I'm going to be doing a bit of shagging,
and I
want you to be okay with it.
I don't want you to be asking me who my
friend is when
my bedroom door's closed at 10:00 a.m.
on a Sunday morning.
I want you to just vacate the property so
I can kick him out.
You get to see more time with me.
I get to spend more time with you.
But there are boundaries." So many of you
with the onset of your business, even if
you move to Dubai,
you're going to get half-priced everything
because you don't pay
tax. If you can relocate
and situate your business to where you can
have a bigger relative income, again,
you can do well.
Then you have the pressure off of how many
clients you need to survive.
And I'll never forget the main quote of
this book that really kind of opened my
eyes to make the decision to leave the UK
and move to Australia,
which just so happens to be one of the
best things that I ever did, was in my
business, I was doing well. I
was earning good money.
I had good clients.
But there was like a little itch
that I couldn't scratch,
and I wasn't sure what it
was. And then in the book, it says,
"The opposite of happiness is boredom." I
realized I wasn't unhappy. Everything
was good. I was just bored.
And for so many of you,
you might get paid well in your corporate
job.
You might have a good pension. But
if you're bored,
it's kind of like a bit of a
disease. It's a disease
that doesn't show up in your blood work.
You could go to get bloods, perfect panel,
everything's looking
good. But slowly, boredom
is just eating away at your brain
and rotting you.
And the question I pose you at the end of
this video is, even if you were to earn
half or two-thirds of what you earn now,
but you weren't bored and you enjoyed it,
would you do it? Most of you say yeah.
And the final thing that's not in this
book, this is actually one of my quotes,
is for years, I did jobs I hated,
that I loathed, whether
recruitment,
working in a sales call center,
whatever it was. I always did well.
But in the back of my mind, I thought,
"Oh, if I do my own thing,
if I start my own
business, what if I fail? What if I fail?
What if I fail?" But the truth is,
if I do well at a job I hate,
imagine how well you could do at a job
that you actually love.
And that's the harsh reality.
If you're doing well
or killing it in a job you hate,
only imagine what you could do
if you put that effort into a job
that you loved.
So now you don't really need to read the
book.
What you need to do
is get the fuck on with it.
Don't care what your profession is.
Build a social media following.
Some of you worried, "Oh,
what do I sell?" I don't
care. Build the following first.
So many of your problems go away.
Once you've built the following,
micro test some products.
Put some things out there.
See what your audience resonate with.
Then, out of all the things you put out,
which one is performing the best?
Double down on that.
Once you double down on that,
work really hard to get more
people joining your business
that end up leaving.
I've written a self-help book, right?
And let me tell you this.
When you start earning good money,
you don't need self-help books.
I almost feel like these books,
and I'm guilty of it, are written to
make people happy
that just aren't doing that well.
If your businesses perform better,
if you loved what you did for a living,
and
you're making more than enough money than
you needed, and you became one of the new
rich, there is not one self-help book
that can make you feel better because you
will already feel fucking awesome.
So get the fuck on with it.
Start getting at it.
Start getting to work.
I help small personal brands build their
brand and business
using social media.
There'll be links in the description as
normal.
Hope you enjoyed the video.
See you in a bit. Bye bye.